<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: scrum | Mattias Liljeson]]></title>
  <link href="http://MattiasLiljeson.github.io/blog/categories/scrum/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://MattiasLiljeson.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2014-01-27T23:50:15+01:00</updated>
  <id>http://MattiasLiljeson.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Mattias Liljeson]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[The little cheese boy]]></title>
    <link href="http://MattiasLiljeson.github.io/blog/2014/01/25/the-little-cheese-boy/"/>
    <updated>2014-01-25T11:09:15+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://MattiasLiljeson.github.io/blog/2014/01/25/the-little-cheese-boy</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>In the autumn of 2012, together with some friends, I made a small pac-man clone with a twist in a project course. The goal with this project was to get a grip on Agile methodologies, especially Scrum, and to successfully deliver a cross-platform game. In the end, I think we got a cute little game together which the &ldquo;client&rdquo; (a prof. acting client) seemed to like a lot.</p>

<!-- more -->




<iframe width="560" height="315" src="http://www.indiedb.com/media/iframe/725823" frameborder="0" scrolling="no" allowfullscreen></iframe>


<p>The &ldquo;client&rsquo;s&rdquo; requirements where a cross-platform game running both Windows and Linux. The Windows version were to use DirectX11 and the Linux version was required to use OpenGL 4. We used a data-oriented approach when communicating with the two render back-ends which made the whole cross-platfrom thing nearly breeze. A part from some driver issues on our Linux machine. We used Visual studio 2010 when developing the game. I created a custom make-file that parsed the solutions project folders and compiled and linked the game with the required libraries and dependencies. I also wrote a couple small sh-scripts that pulled the whole thing from GitHub, built it and emailed any erroneous output to a specified email adress. This was then triggered to run from a cron-script each lunch and each night. This proved to be a quite simple and lightweight way to do automated builds and continuous integration. The code is released under the MIT license and can be downloaded on <a href="https://github.com/MattiasLiljeson/denLilleOstPojken">GitHub</a>. You can see more videos and images on the <a href="http://www.indiedb.com/games/the-little-cheese-boy">IndieDB</a> page. You can also download a compiled version from there</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
